The will was sent back to the capital
유언이 담긴 조서가 도성으로 전해지고
Xie Xuan was ordered to assist in governance
사현이 명을 받아 보정대신을 맡았으며
Crown Prince Sikong Sheng successfully ascended the throne
태자 사공성이 순조롭게 즉위하였고
Posthumously titled you as Emperor Xuancheng
선황에게는 선성제(宣成帝)라는 시호를 올리고
And changed the era name to Taian the following year
이듬해 연호를 태안(泰安)으로 변경합니다
After Sikong Sheng ascended the throne
사공성이 즉위한 후
Although nominally the ruler of all under heaven
명색이 천하의 주인이었지만
The army still had many remnants of Sikong Xu's faction
군대에는 여전히 사공욱의 파벌이 남아 있어
Threatening the state's stability
나라의 안정을 위협하고 있었습니다
Grand General Zhu Yuanzhi, in the name of intimidating border tribes
대장군 주원지는 변방 오랑캐를 제압한다는 명분으로
Stationed troops at the Yan Bei border
연북 변방에 군대를 주둔시켰습니다
Regarding this
이에 대해
Sikong Sheng adopted a strategy of divide and conquer
사공성은 분할 통치의 전략을 취했습니다
On one hand
한편으로는
Forgiving the past
과거의 일은 묻지 않고
And giving rewards to all
모두에게 포상을 내렸으며
On the other hand
다른 한편으로는
For those who repeatedly disobeyed court orders
여러 차례 조정의 명령을 따르지 않는 자들에게
Carrying out targeted punishment
선별적인 처벌을 가했습니다
Although this was effective
이러한 조치가 효과를 보이긴 했지만
Many of the Prince of Yan's former subordinates, though appearing to submit
연왕의 옛 부하들 다수는 겉으로만 귀순했을 뿐
Still harbored resentment in their hearts
마음속에는 여전히 앙금이 남아 있었습니다
And after Zhu Yuanzhi was summoned to the capital
주원지가 도성으로 소환되어
And given a nominal position
실권을 잃은 후에는
Became even more closely connected
더욱 왕래가 잦아졌습니다
The fourth year of Taian
태안 4년
Sikong Sheng, in the name of returning to the old capital
사공성은 옛 도읍을 회복한다는 명분으로
Wished to move the capital to Yong'an
영안으로 천도하여
Moving the political center north
정치 중심을 북쪽으로 이전하려 하지만
Met with fierce opposition from Zhu Yuanzhi
주원지가 기존의 문벌 사족 세력과 연합해
United with old friends, noble families, and scholar clans
격렬히 반대하면서
Finally forced to abandon the plan
결국 흐지부지될 수밖에 없었습니다